Sentence #,Sentence,Tag
Sentence: 71,It meets three times a year .,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 101,"“The forest is our supermarket,” says Anstice Justin.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 102,“We get almost everything from the forests on these islands.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 103,"It is what we survive on.” Mr Justin, an anthropologist, has grown up in the Andaman and Nicobar islands straddling India’s east coast.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 104,"A federally-administered territory, the ecologically-fragile region consists of 836 islands, of which only 38 are inhabited.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 105,"The Nicobar Islands are a distinct group of islands in the southern part of the territory, located some 150 km (93 miles) south of the Andaman Islands.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 106,"Now Mr Justin watches with trepidation as India plans a multi-billion ‘Hong Kong-like’ development project on the Great Nicobar Island, one of the largest and most secluded parts of the Nicobar archipelago.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 107,"Built on a budget of 720bn rupees ($9bn or £6bn) and spread over 166 sq km, the project includes a transshipment harbour, a power plant, an airport and a new township, all designed to link the area to crucial global trade routes along the Indian Ocean and the Suez Canal.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 108,"Positioned near the Strait of Malacca, one of the busiest shipping lanes in the world, the project promises to boost international trade and tourism - the government reckons that some 650,000 people will be living on the island by the time the project is completed in 30 years.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM']"
Sentence: 109,Experts say the multi-billion plan is also a part of India's larger goal to counter China's growing influence in the region.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 110,"But the scheme has sparked alarm among the islanders who fear the loss of their land, culture, and way of life, with the project threatening to push them to the brink of extinction.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 111,"The Andaman and Nicobar Islands are home to some of the most isolated and vulnerable tribes in the world, with five groups classified as ""particularly vulnerable.""","['O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 112,"These include the Jarawas, North Sentinelese, Great Andamanese, Onge, and Shompen.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-PER']"
Sentence: 113,"While the Jarawas and North Sentinelese remain largely uncontacted, the Shompen - some 400 people - of the Great Nicobar Islands are also at risk of losing their way of life due to external pressures.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 114,"A nomadic tribe, most of them live deep inside the forest where they forage for survival - not much is known about their culture as very few of them have ever had contact with the outside world.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 115,"“The loss will be especially huge and traumatic for them,” says Mr Justin, who has been documenting the island since 1985.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM']"
Sentence: 116,“Whatever we call development in the outside world is not of interest to them.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 117,"They have a traditional life of their own.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 118,Environmentalists say there are also huge environmental costs of the project.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 119,"Spread across 921 sq km (355.6 sq miles), around 80% of the Great Nicobar island is covered with rainforests, which are home to more than 1,800 animals and 800 flora species, many of which are endemic.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 120,"The federal environment ministry has said that only 130 sq km or 14% of the total area of the island will be cleared for the project – but that's still about 964,000 trees.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 121,Experts warn the actual number could be much higher.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 122,“The government always claims only a part of the forest will be cleared.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 123,"But the infrastructure you're building would lead to more pollution, which in turn would impact the entire habitat,"" says Madhav Gadgil, an ecologist.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 124,The environment ministry did not respond to BBC's request for comment.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 125,But Environment Minister Bhupendra Yadav in August had said that the project “will not disturb or displace” tribespeople and that it had received environmental clearances based on the “rigour of environmental scrutiny and after incorporating consequent safeguards”.,"['O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 126,"Yet, not everyone is convinced.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 127,"Earlier this year, 39 international experts from different fields of social sciences had warned that the development project would be a “death sentence” for the Shompen as it would destroy their habitat.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 128,"It's a fear that haunts Mr Justin too: ""The Shompen people do not have the knowledge or the means to survive in an industrial world,"" he says.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 129,"He worries the group could meet the same fate as the Nicobarese, the biggest tribal group on the island, which suffered displacement in 2004, when a massive tsunami in the Indian Ocean wiped out their villages.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 130,"Over the years, the government made efforts to resettle the people to a different area - but that too came at a price.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 131,"“Most Nicobarese here are now manual labourers and stay in a settlement instead of their ancestral lands,” Mr Justin says.","['O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 132,"""They have no place to grow crops or keep animals.” There are fears that the project could also expose the Shompen to diseases.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 133,"“Uncontacted peoples have little to no immunity to outside diseases like flu and measles which can and do wipe them out - they typically lose around two thirds of their population after contact,” says Callum Russell, an official at Survival International, a conservation group.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 134,"There are other wider environmental concerns as well, especially about the marine life of the region.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 135,"Ecologists warn of the effect on the Galathea Bay on the south-eastern side of the island, which has been the nesting place for giant leatherback sea turtles for centuries.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 136,"Dr Manish Chandi, a social ecologist, says the project is proposed in an area which is home to saltwater crocodiles and the island's water monitors, fish and avifauna.","['O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 137,A government statement has said the nesting and breeding grounds of these species would not be altered.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 138,"But Mr Chandi points out that there are several other species that nest in the area - such as the Leatherback sea turtles, corals and giant robber crabs - which might get displaced.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 139,"Even though the project would take 30 long years to finish, people can't help but feel anxious about how it will irreversibly alter the delicate balance of both the environment and the lives of the island's indigenous people.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 140,"Follow BBC News India on Instagram, YouTube, Twitter and Facebook.","['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 141,"With winter nights drawing in across North America, Canadian “snowbirds” – citizens who flee their freezing temperatures for sunnier climes every year – are planning their annual trips to Florida or the Caribbean.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 142,"Traditionally, Cuba has been hugely popular among Canadians, drawn to the pristine white sands of beach resorts like Varadero.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 143,They fill the void left by Americans wary of the travel restrictions imposed on them under the continuing US economic embargo of the largest island in the Caribbean.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 144,"Figures show that almost one million Canadian tourists visited Cuba last year, the top country of origin for visitors by some margin.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 145,"As such, a recent decision by the Canadian tour operator, Sunwing Vacations Group – one of Cuba’s leading travel partners – to remove 26 hotels from its Cuba portfolio is a blow to the island’s struggling tourism industry.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 146,"Sunwing took the decision after Cuba endured a four-day nationwide blackout at the end of October, caused by failures with the country's aging energy infrastructure.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 147,"This was followed by another national power cut last month, when Hurricane Rafael barrelled its way across the island, worsening an already-acute electricity crisis.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 148,"A third countrywide blackout then happened on Wednesday, 4 Dec, after Cuba's largest power plant broke down.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 149,"“Cuba has had some volatility in the last few weeks and that may shake consumer confidence,” Sunwing’s chief marketing officer, Samantha Taylor told the Pax News travel website last month.","['B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 150,"“There are incredible places to go in Cuba,” she stressed, keen to emphasise that the company isn’t pulling out of Cuba altogether.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 151,"“But we also recognise that if clients are a little uncomfortable, we need to give them options.” Specifically, that involved drawing up a list of what they called “hidden gems” – alternative holiday destinations in the Dominican Republic, the Bahamas and Colombia.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 152,The implications for Cuba are clear.,"(['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 153,"With tourism now the island’s principal economic motor, and the main source of foreign currency earnings after remittances, that an important tour operator is pointing its customers towards other countries’ beaches over crumbling energy infrastructure is a real concern.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 154,"“Our message to Canadians is that tourism is one of the economy’s priorities,” said Lessner Gómez, director of the Cuban Tourism Board in Toronto in a statement.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 155,"“The Ministry of Tourism has been preparing for the winter season to deliver better services, uninterrupted supplies, a better airport experience, and more and new car rentals.” While Cuba’s tourism agency tries to ease fears about the extent of the electricity blackouts, few can deny that these have been extremely difficult months on the island.","(['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 156,Hurricane Rafael was only the latest storm to hit Cuba in a frenetic Atlantic hurricane season in which more powerful and more frequent storms are the new normal.,"(['B-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 157,"Of course, severe weather is a problem across the Caribbean.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC'],)"
Sentence: 158,"But for Cuba, there are other complications in play.","(['O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 159,"Donald Trump’s re-election to the White House and his choice for Secretary of State, Marco Rubio, stand to make life even more complicated for Cubans than it already is.","(['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 160,"“This is probably the Cuban Revolution’s hardest moment,” says former Cuban diplomat, Jesús Arboleya.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 161,"“And unfortunately, I see nothing on the horizon whatsoever which allows for an optimistic view of the future of US-Cuba relations.","(['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'I-GPE', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 162,"“Donald Trump has handed US policy towards Cuba to those sectors of the Cuban American right who have essentially lived off anti-Castro policies since their origins.” Mr Arboleya adds that Marco Rubio, currently a US Senator for Florida, is the leading voice among them.","(['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O'],)"
Sentence: 163,He is a Cuban American long opposed to the communist government in Havana.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 164,"His parents were Cubans who moved to the US in 1956, three years before Fidel Castro seized power, but his grandfather fled the Castro-led turn to communism on the island.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 165,“People are horrified by the idea of another Donald Trump presidency.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 166,"It spells real trouble,” echoes Cuban political commentator and editor of Temas magazine, Rafael Hernández.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 167,"Current US policy towards Cuba is “somewhat schizophrenic”, he argues.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 168,"“On the one hand, the State Department facilitates support to the private sector, and [pushes for] economic changes in Cuba.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 169,"But on the other hand, Congress and Senate seem to freeze any advances on those reforms.” The expectation is, however, that a future Secretary of State Rubio will coalesce the US’s Cuba policy around a single idea - maximum pressure on the island by tightening the already-harsh sanctions.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 170,"Cubans fear that could mean the suspension of commercial flights to Cuba, or even the closure of the US Embassy in Havana, which was officially reopened in 2015 after decades of frosty relations.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 171,"If implemented, such steps would be deliberately designed to further harm Cuba’s floundering tourism trade, the aim to hit the communist-run nation when it’s down.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 172,Tourist numbers to Cuba have almost halved since the high point of nearly five million visitors during the Obama-era détente with Cuba.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 173,"Between 2015-2017 US visitors flocked to the island under more relaxed travel restrictions, keen to experience a country that had long been denied them.","['O', 'B-TIM', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 174,"Around the same time, the Cuban government embarked on a major hotel-building spree, confident that demand would remain strong over the next decade.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 175,"However, there followed a double blow to Cuban tourism from which it hasn’t fully recovered.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 176,"First, the Trump Administration rolled back President Obama’s engagement policies, and then the Covid-19 pandemic sent the industry into freefall.","['O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 177,"With many of those hotels now registering much lower occupancy rates than originally predicted, and real difficulties in providing the five-star customer experience as advertised amid the blackouts and shortages, some question the strategy of putting so many eggs in the tourism basket in the first place.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 178,"“Why has Cuba invested 38% [of government funds] on average over the past decade in hotels and infrastructure connected to international tourism, but only 8 to 9% on energy infrastructure?” asks economist Ricardo Torres at the American University in Washington DC.","['O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 179,“It doesn’t make sense.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 180,"The hotels run on electricity.” Even with all the current challenges, most visitors agree that Cuba remains a unique travel experience.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 181,"The cliches – classic cars, cigars and mojitos – still appeal to many, while others prefer to travel the island absorbing its history, culture and music.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 182,"Yet as tour operator Sunwings’ decision to step back shows, some tourists are finding it hard to appreciate Cuba during its energy crisis, especially if it’s about to be exacerbated by a hostile administration – and Secretary of State – in Washington.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 183,It’s that quintessential British tradition that we have been enjoying for hundreds of years.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 184,"The answer to every crisis, a bonding ritual when you welcome someone into your home and the first drink many people wake up to.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 185,"“Fancy a cuppa?” or even simply “Tea?” is music to your ears, right?","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 186,"Well, maybe not for everyone.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 187,"""I suppose there's kind of an association with tea as an old person's drink,"" says Gillie Owen, aged 20.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 188,The student from London says he and his friends prefer water or diet soda drinks.,"['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 189,"Layba, meanwhile, doesn't drink tea at all.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 190,"""I have never liked tea,"" the 20-year-old says.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 191,"""I just think it tastes really off, like, really weird.” It's a stark contrast to her parents who, she says, “really love"" tea.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 192,So is it a generational thing?,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 193,"As a nation, are we falling out of love with tea?","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 194,"Last week, one of Britain’s oldest tea firms, Typhoo Tea, collapsed after a drop in sales.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 195,"The 120-year-old company has been rescued by vape maker Supreme, whose boss says he wants to develop new products under the brand.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 196,"Sandy Chadha told the BBC the tea market was in decline but said Supreme would look to appeal to the younger generation who preferred ""things like iced tea and healthier drinks"".","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 197,"Tea sales volumes have fallen by 4.3% compared with two years ago, according to analysts at NielsenIQ.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 198,"And a recent survey by Mintel suggested less than half the nation, 48%, now drink tea at least once a day.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 199,"Kiti Soininen, food and drink researcher at Mintel, says traditional tea is facing “intense competition” from fruit, herbal, green and speciality black tea.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 200,"Twenty-one-year-old student Dylan says he drinks tea, but not the usual builder's tea - black with a smidge of milk – and prefers to go caffeine free.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 201,"""I drink less tea than my parents definitely.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 202,"I drink Redbush tea and other less ‘tea’ teas,"" he says.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 203,"Shayma, 18, says she also prefers herbal tea, while most of her friends drink coffee.","['-PER', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 204,"She says there are ""so many drinks now” and she hasn’t even heard of Typhoo.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 205,Ms Soininen points to the huge difference between sales of tea and coffee.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 206,"“Sales of ordinary tea stood at £377m in 2023, leaving it far behind instant coffee, at [almost] £1bn,” she says.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 207,"Even instant coffee's popularity is being challenged by the fast-growing ready-to-drink coffee market, she adds, which has seen sales more than double over the last five years.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 208,"Polina Jones from NielsenIQ says while people ""are not falling out of love with tea per se"", the landscape is changing with huge offerings from bubble tea, herbal teas, kombuchas and energy drinks attracting the younger generation.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 209,"If this trend continues, she believes brands should reinvent themselves and figure out how to get into the ready-to-drink space.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 210,"Twinings, for example, has started to offer canned sparkling tea, while bottled kombuchas appeal to students and young professionals buying a meal deal, she says.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 211,"Supreme’s purchase of Typhoo includes two herbal tea brands, Heath & Heather and the London Fruit & Herb Company, as well as specialty tea brand Ridgways.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 212,Analyst Susannah Streeter from Hargreaves Lansdown believes Supreme will incorporate these into wellness brands it already owns.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 213,"Another challenge for black tea is that even for those for whom it is a staple, costs are rising and so they are buying in smaller volumes.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 214,"In 1974, the average family purchased 68g - about 30 tea bags - of tea per person, per week.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 215,"By 2023, that had gone down to 19g - about 10 tea bags – per person, according to government figures.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 216,"""What's particularly telling of the potential long-term threat for black tea is that while all age groups have similarly high usage of tea in the early morning and with breakfast, younger groups are much less likely than older ones to reach for the drink later in the day,"" says Mintel’s Kiti Soininen.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 217,"She concludes with a stark warning for traditional tea makers – if younger generations continue with these habits as they get older, this will ultimately “chip away” at the size of the market.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 218,"And as one BBC reader commented on the Typhoo collapse story: ""You know things are bad when a tea company in the UK goes bust.”","['-PER', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 219,A pair of ruby red slippers worn by actress Judy Garland in the classic movie The Wizard of Oz have been sold for $28m (£22m) at a US-based auction on Saturday.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 220,"One of four surviving pairs used in the film, the famed sequined pumps were once stolen from a Minnesota museum.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 221,"Online bidding started a month ago, with the slippers expected to fetch as much as $3m (£2.35m) at auction, according to Heritage Auctions - an under-estimate by $25m (£20m).","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O']"
Sentence: 222,"The auctioneers called the slippers the ""Holy Grail of Hollywood memorabilia"" and said their selling price made them the most valuable movie memorabilia ever sold at auction.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 223,"The winning bid prompted applause in the auction room in Dallas, with the sale coinciding with a renewed interest in the musical following the recent release of the prequel movie Wicked.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 224,Garland was only 16 when she played Dorothy in the classic 1939 musical The Wizard of Oz.,"['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ART', 'I-ART', 'I-ART', 'I-ART']"
Sentence: 225,"Media outlet Variety ranked it second in its inaugural list of ""100 Greatest Movies of All Time"".","['O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 226,The film is a musical adaptation of L Frank Baum's 1900 children's book The Wonderful Wizard of Oz.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'B-ART', 'I-ART', 'I-ART', 'I-ART', 'I-ART']"
Sentence: 227,"While in the book, the magical slippers are silver, the producers for the film changed them to red to take advantage of the new Technicolor technology.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 228,"In the film, as in the book, a pivotal moment occurs when Dorothy must click her heels three times as she repeats ""There's no place like home"" in order to leave the magical land of Oz and return to Kansas and her Auntie Em.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 229,"While several pairs of shoes were worn by Garland during filming, only four are known to have survived.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 230,One of the pairs is on exhibit at the Smithsonian's National Museum of American History.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
Sentence: 231,But this pair up for auction has its own unique history.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 232,"Collector Michael Shaw had loaned the slippers out to the Judy Garland Museum in her hometown of Grand Rapids, Minnesota, when they were stolen in 2005.","['O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM']"
Sentence: 233,"Professional thief Terry Jon Martin used a hammer to smash the glass case and snatch the slippers, believing that their insured value of $1m must be because they were covered in actual gemstones.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 234,"But when he took them to a ""fence"" - an intermediary who sells stolen goods to discreet buyers - he discovered they were just glass.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 235,So he gave the shoes to someone else.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 236,It wasn't until 2018 that the FBI recovered the shoes in a sting operation.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 237,What happened to them in those 13 years is still not known.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 238,"In 2023, Martin - who was in his 70s and used a wheelchair - pleaded guilty to stealing them, and was sentenced to time served.","['O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 239,"""There's some closure, and we do know definitely that Terry Jon Martin did break into our museum, but I'd like to know what happened to them after he let them go,"" John Kelsch, curator of the Judy Garland Museum, told CBS News Minnesota in 2023.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-TIM']"
Sentence: 240,"""Just to do it because he thought they were real rubies and to turn them over to a jewelry fence.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 241,"I mean, the value is not rubies.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 242,"The value is an American treasure, a national treasure.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 243,"To steal them without knowing that seems ludicrous.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 244,"With winter nights drawing in across North America, Canadian “snowbirds” – citizens who flee their freezing temperatures for sunnier climes every year – are planning their annual trips to Florida or the Caribbean.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 245,"Traditionally, Cuba has been hugely popular among Canadians, drawn to the pristine white sands of beach resorts like Varadero.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 246,They fill the void left by Americans wary of the travel restrictions imposed on them under the continuing US economic embargo of the largest island in the Caribbean.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 247,"Figures show that almost one million Canadian tourists visited Cuba last year, the top country of origin for visitors by some margin.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 248,"As such, a recent decision by the Canadian tour operator, Sunwing Vacations Group – one of Cuba’s leading travel partners – to remove 26 hotels from its Cuba portfolio is a blow to the island’s struggling tourism industry.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 249,"Sunwing took the decision after Cuba endured a four-day nationwide blackout at the end of October, caused by failures with the country's aging energy infrastructure.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 250,"This was followed by another national power cut last month, when Hurricane Rafael barrelled its way across the island, worsening an already-acute electricity crisis.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 251,"A third countrywide blackout then happened on Wednesday, 4 Dec, after Cuba's largest power plant broke down.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 252,"“Cuba has had some volatility in the last few weeks and that may shake consumer confidence,” Sunwing’s chief marketing officer, Samantha Taylor told the Pax News travel website last month.","['B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 253,"“There are incredible places to go in Cuba,” she stressed, keen to emphasise that the company isn’t pulling out of Cuba altogether.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 254,"“But we also recognise that if clients are a little uncomfortable, we need to give them options.” Specifically, that involved drawing up a list of what they called “hidden gems” – alternative holiday destinations in the Dominican Republic, the Bahamas and Colombia.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 255,The implications for Cuba are clear.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 256,"With tourism now the island’s principal economic motor, and the main source of foreign currency earnings after remittances, that an important tour operator is pointing its customers towards other countries’ beaches over crumbling energy infrastructure is a real concern.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 257,"“Our message to Canadians is that tourism is one of the economy’s priorities,” said Lessner Gómez, director of the Cuban Tourism Board in Toronto in a statement.","['O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 258,"“The Ministry of Tourism has been preparing for the winter season to deliver better services, uninterrupted supplies, a better airport experience, and more and new car rentals.” While Cuba’s tourism agency tries to ease fears about the extent of the electricity blackouts, few can deny that these have been extremely difficult months on the island.","['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 259,Hurricane Rafael was only the latest storm to hit Cuba in a frenetic Atlantic hurricane season in which more powerful and more frequent storms are the new normal.,"['B-MISC', 'I-MISC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 260,"Of course, severe weather is a problem across the Caribbean.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 261,"But for Cuba, there are other complications in play.","['O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 262,"Donald Trump’s re-election to the White House and his choice for Secretary of State, Marco Rubio, stand to make life even more complicated for Cubans than it already is.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 263,"“This is probably the Cuban Revolution’s hardest moment,” says former Cuban diplomat, Jesús Arboleya.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 264,"“And unfortunately, I see nothing on the horizon whatsoever which allows for an optimistic view of the future of US-Cuba relations.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'I-GPE', 'O']"
Sentence: 265,"“Donald Trump has handed US policy towards Cuba to those sectors of the Cuban American right who have essentially lived off anti-Castro policies since their origins.” Mr Arboleya adds that Marco Rubio, currently a US Senator for Florida, is the leading voice among them.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 266,He is a Cuban American long opposed to the communist government in Havana.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 267,"His parents were Cubans who moved to the US in 1956, three years before Fidel Castro seized power, but his grandfather fled the Castro-led turn to communism on the island.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 268,“People are horrified by the idea of another Donald Trump presidency.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 269,"It spells real trouble,” echoes Cuban political commentator and editor of Temas magazine, Rafael Hernández.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 270,"Current US policy towards Cuba is “somewhat schizophrenic”, he argues.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 271,"“On the one hand, the State Department facilitates support to the private sector, and [pushes for] economic changes in Cuba.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 272,"But on the other hand, Congress and Senate seem to freeze any advances on those reforms.” The expectation is, however, that a future Secretary of State Rubio will coalesce the US’s Cuba policy around a single idea - maximum pressure on the island by tightening the already-harsh sanctions.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 273,"Cubans fear that could mean the suspension of commercial flights to Cuba, or even the closure of the US Embassy in Havana, which was officially reopened in 2015 after decades of frosty relations.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 274,"If implemented, such steps would be deliberately designed to further harm Cuba’s floundering tourism trade, the aim to hit the communist-run nation when it’s down.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 275,Tourist numbers to Cuba have almost halved since the high point of nearly five million visitors during the Obama-era détente with Cuba.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 276,"Between 2015-2017 US visitors flocked to the island under more relaxed travel restrictions, keen to experience a country that had long been denied them.","['O', 'B-TIM', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 277,"Around the same time, the Cuban government embarked on a major hotel-building spree, confident that demand would remain strong over the next decade.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 278,"However, there followed a double blow to Cuban tourism from which it hasn’t fully recovered.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 279,"First, the Trump Administration rolled back President Obama’s engagement policies, and then the Covid-19 pandemic sent the industry into freefall.","['O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 280,"With many of those hotels now registering much lower occupancy rates than originally predicted, and real difficulties in providing the five-star customer experience as advertised amid the blackouts and shortages, some question the strategy of putting so many eggs in the tourism basket in the first place.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 281,"“Why has Cuba invested 38% [of government funds] on average over the past decade in hotels and infrastructure connected to international tourism, but only 8 to 9% on energy infrastructure?” asks economist Ricardo Torres at the American University in Washington DC.","['O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 282,“It doesn’t make sense.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 283,"The hotels run on electricity.” Even with all the current challenges, most visitors agree that Cuba remains a unique travel experience.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 284,"The cliches – classic cars, cigars and mojitos – still appeal to many, while others prefer to travel the island absorbing its history, culture and music.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 285,"Yet as tour operator Sunwings’ decision to step back shows, some tourists are finding it hard to appreciate Cuba during its energy crisis, especially if it’s about to be exacerbated by a hostile administration – and Secretary of State – in Washington.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 286,"Closer relations between the UK and the European Union (EU) will boost economic growth, Chancellor Rachel Reeves will tell finance leaders on Monday.","['B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM']"
Sentence: 287,"In the first address by a British chancellor to the Eurogroup since Brexit, Reeves will say that a ""reset"" in relations would mean ""breaking down barriers to trade"" as well as helping ""businesses sell in each other's markets"".","['B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-MISC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 288,"While Labour has ruled out re-joining the trade bloc, it has repeatedly said it wants the UK to ""deepen ties"" with the EU.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 289,"The Conservatives said the chancellor should instead be working out how to reverse the ""devastating Budget measures that have crashed confidence"".","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 290,"The British Chambers of Commerce (BCC), which represents about 50,000 businesses, said that in order for the economy to grow ""we must export more"" but UK firms ""are struggling under huge regulatory and paperwork burdens"".","['B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 291,"At the Eurogroup finance ministers meeting in Brussels, Reeves will propose building a ""mature, business-like relationship"" between Britain and the EU.","['O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 292,"""I know that the last few years have been fractious,"" she will tell her European counterparts.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 293,"""Division and chaos defined the last government's approach to Europe.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O']"
Sentence: 294,"It will not define ours.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 295,"She will say: ""I believe that a closer economic relationship between the UK and the EU is not a zero-sum game.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 296,"It's about improving both our growth prospects.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 297,"While this speech is not expected to result in any changes on Labour's manifesto promise not to re-join the EU's single market or customs union, it is likely to mean an agreement on food and farm exports, with the UK having said it is seeking a veterinary agreement.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 298,"It could also mean less red tape on more complex pan-European supply chains in manufacturing and textiles, but big trade-offs may be necessary.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 299,The EU would like to see a scheme for young Europeans to live and work both there and in the UK - something Sir Keir Starmer has ruled out in the past.,"['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 300,Closer alignment to European food standards could also complicate any attempt by the UK to forge closer relations with the US on Donald Trump's re-entry into the White House in January.,"['B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-TIM']"
Sentence: 301,"Ahead of the chancellor's speech, shadow business secretary Andrew Griffith urged her to ""jump on a plane to the US and talk to [President-elect] Trump about getting a US-UK trade deal done, not trying to take Britain backwards into the slow growth EU.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 302,"But Liberal Democrat Treasury spokesperson Daisy Cooper said: ""The Conservatives' botched Brexit deal has been a disaster for the economy, with small businesses, farmers and fishers all caught up in endless red tape.""","['B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-MISC', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 303,"Last month in a highly unusual move, the governor of the Bank of England, Andrew Bailey, said that the UK must ""rebuild relations"" with the EU.","['B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 304,The governor has avoided commenting on Brexit because of the Bank's independence from Westminster politics.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 305,"""The impact on trade seems to be more in goods than services,"" he said.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 306,"""But it underlines why we must be alert to and welcome opportunities to rebuild relations while respecting that very important decision of the British people.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 307,"The export of goods, such as in food and farming, has been impacted by new trade barriers.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 308,"But services, including banking, have performed better than expected.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 309,Labour has said it is committed to implementing post-Brexit agreements struck under the previous Tory government.,"['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 310,"These include the Windsor Framework, which covers trade between the UK and Northern Ireland.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ART', 'I-ART', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC']"
Sentence: 311,"But Reeves will tell finance ministers: ""The reset in relations is about doing what is the best interests of our shared economies and those that depend on it.","['O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 312,"""That means breaking down barriers to trade, creating opportunities to invest and helping our businesses sell in each other's markets.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 313,Reeves will give her speech at a key time for both the UK and European economies after President-elect Donald Trump threatened to impose tariffs of up to 20% on all goods imported into the US.,"['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 314,"Carsten Brzeski, global head at financial services company ING Research, told the BBC's Today programme that European leaders ""clearly"" had an interest in working more closely with the UK government as a result of Trump's election.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 315,"He said that potential tariff changes could prove a ""threat"" to European economies such as Germany, who export a great deal of goods to the US.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 316,"""It's also about Donald Trump's idea to cut taxes and do deregulation in the US.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE']"
Sentence: 317,"That could also make the US economy much more attractive than the EU economy and could somewhat cannibalise the growth potential of Europe,"" Mr Brzeski said.","['O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER']"
Sentence: 318,"Sign up for our Politics Essential newsletter to read top political analysis, gain insight from across the UK and stay up to speed with the big moments.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 319,It'll be delivered straight to your inbox every weekday.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 320,"Not long after buying and publicly consuming a $6.2m banana as part of an artworld stunt, Chinese crypto entrepreneur Justin Sun made another eye-catching purchase, investing $30m ($23.5m) into a cryptocurrency firm called World Liberty Financial.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'B-ART', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
Sentence: 321,"The company had foundered since its October launch, investors seemingly leery of its prospects and its terms.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 322,But it boasted a potentially enticing feature: the chance to do business with a firm partnering with and promoted by none other than Donald Trump.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER']"
Sentence: 323,Mr Sun's investment tipped the company over the threshold that allowed the president-elect to begin profiting from the venture.,"['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 324,Trump and his family are now in the position to collect roughly $20m - and potentially far more.,"['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O']"
Sentence: 325,"Mr Sun, who is currently fighting fraud charges in the US related to his own crypto business, did not respond to questions about what prompted his interest in the tokens, which cannot be traded.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 326,"But the episode set off alarm bells among government ethics experts, who see it as an indication that Trump's expanding business ventures have made it easier than ever for those hoping to influence US policy to steer money his way.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 327,"""The conflicts have grown substantially with the scope of his business empire,"" said Richard Painter, who served as the White House's chief ethics lawyer during the George W Bush administration.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER']"
Sentence: 328,"In a statement to the BBC, Trump's team shrugged off the worries.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 329,"In his first term, ""President Trump removed himself from his multi-billion-dollar real estate empire to run for office and forewent his government salary,"" Trump spokeswoman Karoline Leavitt said.","['O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 330,"""Unlike most politicians, President Trump didn't get into politics for profit – he's fighting because he loves the people of this country and wants to make America great again.""","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'B-LOC']"
Sentence: 331,"But Trump has taken little action in response to concerns about the potential for corruption, or appearance of it, as he prepares for a return to the White House.","['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 332,Trump has faced questions about conflicts of interest before.,"['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 333,"During his first term as president, the Trump International Hotel in Washington, DC became a symbol of the issue, as a go-to place for lobbyists, foreign diplomats, and allies to stay and spend.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 334,Critics argued that the hotel created a way for Trump to profit indirectly from his office.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 335,He faced accusations and lawsuits alleging he violated the US Constitution's ban on presidents receiving foreign emoluments – or profiting from their office.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-GPE', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 336,"But experts said the growth of his business empire, which now includes a publicly traded social media company, a cryptocurrency firm, and ties to a Saudi-backed golf league, makes it possible for anyone hoping to curry favour to move money more quietly and in much greater sums.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O']"
Sentence: 337,"""The scale has increased and the ease has increased,"" said Michael Ohlrogge, a law professor at New York University, who has studied Trump Media, which operates Truth Social and currently represents the bulk of Trump's $6bn fortune.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O']"
Sentence: 338,"""You can only book so many hotel rooms.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 339,"On Truth Social, for example, Prof Ohlrogge said a foreign government or business could purchase ads convincing investors the firm was gaining traction, prompting a pop in its share price.","['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 340,"Though Trump Media commands a market value of more than $7bn, there has been little sign of such activity so far.","['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 341,The company reported less than $5m in ad sales this year.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-CUR', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 342,"But given the stock market's ""amplifying"" effect, Prof Ohlrogge said it would not require a lot of spending to lead to potentially significant gains for Trump, who owns more than half the shares of the company.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 343,"Nowhere is the entanglement between Trump's business interests and his public duties as stark as in the crypto industry, where he has deepened his personal involvement, while simultaneously promising to champion it while in the White House.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O']"
Sentence: 344,"His plans include regulatory rollback and ideas such as a national Bitcoin reserve, in which the government would stockpile the cryptocurrency.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 345,"""One of the most important issues to be determined over the next couple years is how crypto is regulated,"" said Virginia Canter, chief ethics counsel at the nonpartisan Citizens for Responsibility and Ethics in Washington.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
Sentence: 346,"""Well now, he's an active player in the crypto market.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 347,"How it could be regulated [could] affect his personal wealth, what kind of position he takes.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 348,"Nik Bhatia, founder of Bitcoin Layer, a firm that advocates investments in Bitcoin, said it would be a mistake to dismiss Trump's stance on crypto as driven only by his own financial interests.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 349,"""I don't see these moves motivated by self-interest - I see them representing the electorate,"" he said.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 350,"But still, he said: ""I think there probably is a conflict of interest in that his pro-crypto stance will benefit his company.""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 351,"This week, Trump said he would nominate Paul Atkins, who has lobbied for the industry, to lead the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC).","['B-TIM', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 352,"He is widely expected to dial back enforcement at the agency, which polices publicly traded firms such as Trump Media for issues such as fraud and insider trading.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 353,The SEC oversaw a crackdown on the crypto industry under President Joe Biden.,"['O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER']"
Sentence: 354,"Mr Sun, the World Liberty Financial investor, was caught up in the SEC crackdown last year, after the agency charged him and his company with failing to properly register with the government while selling certain digital assets, among other charges.","['B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 355,"Under new leadership, the agency could very well drop the case, said John Coffee, a professor at Columbia Law School and an expert in securities law.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 356,"""The leading characteristic of Mr Atkins is that he does not like enforcement and wants to greatly restrict the range of cases the SEC will bring,"" he said.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 357,"In announcing his investment last month, Mr Sun did not mention the SEC complaint - which he has said lacks merit - but did cite Trump's views on crypto.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 358,"""The U.S. is becoming the blockchain hub, and Bitcoin owes it to @realDonaldTrump!""","['O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 359,he wrote on X.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG']"
Sentence: 360,"""TRON is committed to making America great again and leading innovation.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 361,"Let's go!""","['O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 362,There is little in US law that sets limits on conflict-of-interest - presidents are not bound by the same rules that regulate other government employees and cabinet officials.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 363,"Though the US Constitution in theory bars presidents from taking presents from foreign governments while in office, the Supreme Court already has dismissed two previous lawsuits from Trump's first term involving potential conflicts of interests.","['O', 'B-LOC', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 364,"Last summer, in a case involving Trump, it also ruled that presidents have broad immunity from criminal prosecution while in office.","['B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 365,"In the past, Trump has argued that his business was actually hurt by his time in the White House, as partners worried about controversy cut ties, and he faced investigations and lawsuits.","['O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 366,"Now preparing to enter the White House a second time, Trump has yet to unveil an ethics plan, as is customary, and has given little sign he plans to bow to such concerns.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'I-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 367,"He has vowed to hold onto his Trump Media stake, continues to hawk Trump-branded merchandise and lend his name to ventures like World Liberty Financial.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG']"
Sentence: 368,His Mar-a-Lago club remains a place where the wealthy willing to pay for membership can gain access to the president with little to no transparency.,"['O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 369,Ethics experts worry that Trump has opened a door that will be difficult to close again.,"['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 370,"""Trump's got the message he can do whatever he wants, because he won,"" Mr Painter said.","['B-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O']"
Sentence: 371,"""Future presidents are going to look at this and think, 'We can do whatever we want.'""","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 372,"""Jaguar has no desire to be loved by everybody,"" said Gerry McGovern as he strode across the stage on a slightly chilly evening in Miami last week.","['B-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-PER', 'I-PER', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O']"
Sentence: 373,"It was a bold statement from Jaguar Land Rover's creative director, but it summed up the aura around the relaunch of one of the UK's most famous brands.","['O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'I-ORG', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'B-LOC', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 374,"On 18 November, a short teaser ad was released that ignited social media.","['O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
Sentence: 375,"Lasting just 30 seconds, it showed models in bizarre and brightly coloured outfits but did not feature a single car.","['O', 'O', 'B-TIM', 'I-TIM', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O', 'O']"
